Danh Tran

Senior Software Engineer

As a software developer with 6 years of experience, I have worked in both Games & Apps Development. I'm easy to adapt to new tasks, and very patient with the legacy codebase. I'd like to dig into the architecture, optimize the code, spend time to debug, and always think about "How to make it faster?" or "Is this code easy to understand?". Ideally, I hope to develop my career in Android Apps Development. I believe that my contribution to your company will be valuable for the products.



- ✓ danhtran.dev@outlook.com
- Pho Chi Minh, Vietnam
- github.com/danhtran-dev

- +84374268537
- in linkedin.com/in/danhtrandev
- medium.com/@danhtran-dev

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer ShopBack Group

03/2022 - Present

The ShopBack Group is Asia-Pacific's leading shopping and rewards platform, serving over 30 million shoppers across ten markets.

Responsibilities

- PIC of product Earn More & Challenge on Android. I contribute to the ideation, technical design, implementation, and unit testing for Android.
- Work with Product Design, Product Operation, and the QA team to implement new features and support our users' satisfaction.
- Collaborate with other Tech Teams to contribute technical design discussions.

Senior Software Engineer Zalo Group

04/2018 - 03/2022

Zalo Group builds world-class tech products used and loved by millions. Products: Zalo, Zing TV, Zing MP3, Bao Moi, Laban Key, Adtima.

Responsibilities

- Collaborate with the Product Design team to define, design, and refine product features.
- In charge of features such as Sticker, Voice, Edit Photo, Video, Messages Database, and more ... to produce user's needs
- Maintain the existing codebase and optimize performance and fix critical production bugs and deliver them on time.

Game Developer

VNG Corp

09/2017 - 04/2018

VNG develops, produces, and publishes games to the global market Responsibilities

 Maintain the existing codebase, fix technical problems, and optimize the performance of the legacy source code.

Game Developer

YOMI Studio

04/2017 - 09/2017

A Game Studio produce mini-games on mobile to the global market Responsibilities

• Maintain the existing codebase and fix technical problems.

SKILLS

Android Clean Architecture Java/Kotlin C++

SQLite RxJava Retrofit MVVM MVP

Unit Test

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Been Together App

• This app has over 1.000.000 downloads and 9.000 positive reviews

KBC Trivia & Quiz Game

 A Quiz game like "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?" TV Show. This game was published in India Google Play Store and got 5 millions downloads with thousands of positive reviews

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree

University Information of Technology

2012 - 2017

Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

Licenses & certifications

- BIG-O BLUE: INTERMEDIATE ALGORITHMS
- AlgoExpert Certificate

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese Native or Bilingual Proficiency English

Professional Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Technology Crypto Currency Sport Guitar

Games

Poetry